Embryology, as we've just seen, this development of the eye,
we will also integrate it with the skull,
and integrate it with the development of the brain.
Because we will see that the placement of the eye,
which at first, you noticed, develops very laterally,
will at some point come toward the anterior part.
And in fact, it's a whole global development of the body
through the processes of cephalization and...
cardialization and ascent of the brain and descent
visceral
that will organize the eye and conform it to this whole.
So it will follow the entirety of this development.
Thus, it will also result from a visceral descent.
We will see how the palate will become a fulcrum for the eye,
on a cranial level.
We will see that each bone of the skull will have importance
on the proper functioning of the eye.
The function is the resumption of embryogenesis and the establishment of
embryogenesis on a functional level.
If you understand this movement of development, you have the functional strength, you
have the therapeutic power.
Structure, function, and form. One could say that form is structure and function.
When you are in good shape, it means you have good structure and good function.
So form is the expression of this structure
and of this function. Thirdly, this is very important, is that the body
possesses
self-regulatory mechanisms. It has this capacity, you see, through the phenomenon
of allostasis, homeostasis,
to balance itself. Allostasis, you see, is an internal electric process
that brings us back to equilibrium.
This embryonic force, or I would say conversely,
this therapeutic force, this
healing force, is a whole process,
that uses this same quality of energy found in the embryo
to develop a form.
So the development of form, thus from embryology,
is the same energy the body uses to regenerate itself.
It is generated.
Regenerating knowing the developmental processes means knowing the
mapping of this development because it doesn't happen randomly; it happens
in a specific organization. A limb, you see, will first
open
like this before making a movement like that; it's its developmental strength
but it happens simultaneously as I have a whole movement here at
the same time as I have a movement here, as we saw the importance of
the brain. Remember, I had
mimicked the tai chi of each space.
We will review them a little bit and put them back
into the eye. Because the eye
ultimately has the memory of all this.
So the embryonic force,
this energy of development
is the same force that the
body uses to regenerate itself,
to heal itself.
And thus, it will recreate
growth processes to regenerate itself.
Well, if we touch the body
at the right moment, in the right space,
moving into this recognition, it can express itself. Sometimes
it expresses itself later. So trust
this tissue. So we see the eye here that follows the same
levels because ultimately we
travel through different understandings. The function is the
resumption of embryogenesis and the establishment of
embryogenesis on a functional level.
To see that we will also find axes
anatomical axes
also, pure
structural ones, in the structure
but
this is
important
in the end,
it is an electric field
for example.
Sometimes
you treat a tendonitis
and I suggest you reflect
on an electric level.
Because when we work on these axes,
in the brain,
it will not be structural,
it will be electric fields.
Because the eye places itself in a sphere of pure energy,
the search for an electric axis.
This notion of polarity,
which was already integrated from the start,
at the level of the oocyte,
with Wolpert, with this flag,
with these nourishing cells,
follicular with specific metabolic concentrations,
thus,
electrochemical.
Thus, these are molecular-electrical levels, if you will,
that create these movements. And so I
suggest to say, hey,
let's try to think
when we go to a structure
or to an eye, let’s try to think
a bit electrically.
The axis of the eyes is
like rooted, like this.
Because you will see that as it follows
movements, it will make
a spiral movement as well. It is like rooted, in the cranial box, in
the bottom of your sockets.
Viola Freeman said this. And in fact, it's rooted. I like the image of the root, like
this.
So, when we work on the eye, we will see that interesting things
will
appear. We will see how we can work on that. If you look at the roots, they make
movements like that. It's spirals. Because these electromagnetic fields, they rotate like this.
It's not just like that, it's ionic molecular movements
the transduction of a
photon into an electric field is simply changes in permeability
on sonic planes; I change my membrane permeability starting
by changing shape; you see,
we will review this in neurophysiology with rhodopsin, opsins, and
meta-rhodopsins that
change integration to show how these energetic information
will modify
simple changes in membrane shapes.